<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Duc Nguyen</title><link>https://ducng.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Duc Nguyen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 10:01:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ducng.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a MPRIS server in Go</title><link>https://ducng.github.io/posts/mpris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 17:48:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ducng.github.io/posts/mpris/</guid><description>Why? The use case of creating a MPRIS server is basically when you&amp;rsquo;re making a music player and want to broadcast metadata to the system. Since I was creating a webradio player in Go, I needed this feature.
There are a lot of documentation online (and even lib) on how to create a MPRIS client to retrieve currently playing metadata but a lot less when it comes to creating an actual server.</description></item><item><title>Managing a music library using beets</title><link>https://ducng.github.io/posts/music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 17:22:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ducng.github.io/posts/music/</guid><description>Growing up as a kid I mostly listened music through my nice mp3 player: It created some kind a habit to store music locally and even after streaming platforms were widely used, having limited 3G on my smartphone I mostly relied on playing music stored locally. Over the years, my library grew quiet significantly and became harder and harder to organize. I could at any moment choose the easy pass to just throw everything away and switch everything to a streaming platform but I felt kind of nostalgic and as a tech enthusiast I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just rely on someone elses platform for my needs.</description></item><item><title>Creating an encrypted RAID5 on Linux using mdadm, LUKS and LVM</title><link>https://ducng.github.io/posts/raid5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 18:31:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ducng.github.io/posts/raid5/</guid><description>Having a bunch of unused 1 To HDD and my NAS getting full I decided to take extra steps ensuring my data were safe.
Stuff I already had Custom NAS running Arch Linux (just an old PC) with 2*1 To HDD 2 unused 1 To HDD The idea Having 4 1 To HDD I could potentialy create a RAID 5 with 3 To of usable space ensuring my data were a little more safe.</description></item><item><title>Using 5.1 through S/PDIF on Linux</title><link>https://ducng.github.io/posts/spdif/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 18:07:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ducng.github.io/posts/spdif/</guid><description>Using 5.1 on Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t something very common in the first place. But using it over the S/PDIF is even less common so finding documentation about how to do it is close to impossible. After hours and hours of struggling, I found a working solution so I decided to write an article about it.
What is 5.1? The 5.1 technology allows audio to be sent to the speaker through 6 independant channels: left, right, center, rear left, rear right and the .</description></item></channel></rss>